ratepoint.com 2012-01-10

# Local Business Reviews and Online Reputation Management | RatePoint

Last Updated: July 18, 2011

RatePoint, Inc. ("RatePoint") understands that your privacy is important to you, and we want you to be fully informed and as comfortable as possible visiting the www.ratepoint.com website ("Site") or using the RatePoint products and/or services ("Services"). Our privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") will tell you what information we collect about you and your use of the RatePoint Site and Services, how we use that information, and how we may share it with others. It will explain how we protect that information and what choices you have about how it is used or shared. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully so that you will understand how we protect your privacy and how we may collect, use, and share information.

By visiting the RatePoint Site or using the RatePoint Services, you agree to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by RatePoint and does not apply to advertisers or third parties. Be advised that if you access a third-party site from a link on the RatePoint Site or Services, any information you reveal on that site is not subject to this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to be aware when you leave the RatePoint Site and/or Services and to read the privacy policies of each and every site you visit.

RatePoint has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe's program requirements including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at:

RatePoint, Inc.

145 Rosemary St, Suite D

Needham, Massachusetts- 02494

Phone: 1-781-455-1100

Fax: 1-781-455-1110

If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe here.

Information covered by this Privacy Policy is maintained on RatePoint systems in the United States. For information relating to identified or identifiable natural persons ("Personal Information") provided by our European Union business partners, RatePoint adheres to the US-EU Safe Harbor Privacy Principles set forth at http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/SH_Privacy.asp.

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, feel free to contact us at privacy@ratepoint.com. Capitalized terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as set forth in the RatePoint Terms of Service unless otherwise indicated.

### 1\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT

At RatePoint we value your privacy. Our primary purpose in collecting information about you is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient and customized experience and to provide services and features that are most likely to meet your needs.

Information We Automatically Collect. We automatically receive, store and track information collected via traditional web site analytics processes whenever you interact with the RatePoint Site or Services regardless of whether you are a registered User. Such information includes demographic information, browser type and additional non-personal information. We use this information to do internal research on our Users' demographics, interests and behaviors in order to better understand, protect and serve you and the RatePoint community. 

Log Files. Like many websites, we automatically gather certain non-personal information about our Site and Services traffic and store it in log files. This information may include: Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type and version, referring/exit pages, operating system and platform, date and time, and pages viewed or searched for. We use this information to analyze trends, and to administer the Site and Services. 

Cookies. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a User's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on our Site and with our Services and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses the RatePoint Site or Services. In addition to some of the same information as gathered in the log files, the information we collect in the cookie may include a unique identifier for tracking your activity. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. 

You may use the RatePoint Site or Services anonymously by prohibiting the use of cookies on your machine, however, your ability to use many features of our Site and Services will be limited. 

We may use session cookies. A session cookie expires and is deleted from your computer when you close your browser. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our Site and to receive the greatest benefit from our Site and Services. 

Third Party Cookies. The use of cookies by third parties is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. These third parties use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. 

Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs). Our third party advertising partner employs] a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information. 

Information we Collect From You 

During Registration. RatePoint Business Members are required to register in order to use Services. Each RatePoint Business Member must provide the Business Name, Business Address, Phone number, administrator's Name, administrator's e-mail address, and the administrator's password. If you wish to upgrade your account we will financial information from you such as credit card number, expiration date and billing address. 

We use this information to contact you about the services on our site in which you have expressed interest, to respond to your inquiries, to send you notifications when you receive new reviews, and to bill you for services. 

RatePoint Users are not required to register in order to visit our Site or use many of our Services. However, if you would like to submit a review, you must first register with RatePoint by providing an e-mail address and possibly a password and/or telephone number. 

Customer Reviews. We post customer reviews on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the review to post their name along with their review. 

Import Contacts. We utilize an import contacts feature to help the RatePoint Business Member to manage and communicate with contacts in which a relationship already exists. Additionally, RatePoint provides an opt-in subscription service that allows a RatePoint Business Member to collect contacts for management and communication utilizing the RatePoint service. Notifications will be sent to RatePoint Business Member contacts only in the case of using the subscription service. These notifications are sent from RatePoint on behalf of the RatePoint business member. 

We allow RatePoint Business Members to manually upload contacts on an as needed basis. The process of uploading contacts requires that a RatePoint Business Memeber either connect to a RatePoint Business Member’s email service (like Gmail, Hotmail, Yahoo. Etc…) or provide a file with contact details. In each case contact information, such as email address, will be imported into the RatePoint environment. RatePoint Business Members must agree that these contacts are opt-in and/or have a relationship with the RatePoint Business Member. 

The information we collect about the RatePoint Business Member contacts is name, address, email address, company information, and other standard contact information. The amount of information you enter for each contact is at your own discretion. We do not use this information for any purpose, we just allow you the option to store this information within your account for your own use. 

All RatePoint business Members and Users are required to give truthful contact information (such as a valid e-mail address) in accordance with our Terms of Service. 

In addition to basic Site and Services registration data, any individually information, such as name, address, and other personally identifiable information, that you voluntarily provide to RatePoint is considered 'Personal Information’ under this Privacy Policy. Business information including, but not limited to Business Name, Business Address, Phone number, Business website are not considered personal information and may be used by RatePoint to build your public RatePoint Buisness Member profile. You have the option to opt-out and exclude this information to be displayed on your public RatePoint Profile by logging into the RatePoint Business Member’s RatePoint Account. 

Send A Review. If you wish to send a review to a friend to allow them to participate in submitting reviews, we will send your friend a one time email inviting them to submit a review. We store this information for the sole purpose of allowing your friend to submit the review and to track the success of the send a review request program. 

Your friend may contact us at privacy@ratepoint.com to request that we remove this information from our database. 

Correspondence. If you send us personal correspondence, such as e-mails or letters, or if other Users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Site or Services, we may collect and retain such information. 

Business Ideas or Inventions. This Privacy Policy does not protect feedback, business information, ideas, concepts, or inventions that you submit to RatePoint by e-mail or through the Site or Services. If you want to keep business information, ideas, concepts, or inventions private or proprietary, do not send them to RatePoint. RatePoint may use any feedback, information, ideas, concepts or inventions that you provide to RatePoint for any purpose without limitation and without any obligation to compensate you. 

Public Areas. If you use the forum on this Web site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. 

Advertisers. Sponsors, advertisers or other third parties may also use their own cookies when you click on their advertisement or link to their site or service, or even if an advertisement simply appears on a page that you are viewing. Some advertisers use companies other than RatePoint to serve their ads and these companies may also collect non-Personal Information through the use of cookies on our Site and/or Services. We do not control these third parties' use of cookies, or how they manage the non-Personal Information they gather through them. 

Children. We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. RatePoint provides a general audience service that is not designed or intended to attract children under the age of thirteen (13). We do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 13. 

### 2\. CONDITIONS UNDER WHICH WE SHARE INFORMATION

Personal Information. Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, RatePoint will not share, sell, rent or trade your personal information with third parties. 

Disclosure of Aggregate Information (Non-Personal Information). RatePoint may provide to third parties non-Personal Information obtained from you that is combined with the non-Personal Information of other Users and does not allow you to be identified or contacted ("Aggregate Information"). For example, we might provide to third parties Aggregate Information regarding the number of Users of our Services and the activities they conduct while using our Services. We also may not limit the third parties' use of the Aggregate Information, except that we do require third parties to whom we disclose Aggregate Information to agree that they will not attempt to make this information personally identifiable by combining it with other databases or other sources of information. 

Agents/Service Providers. We use other third parties such as a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services. We use Live Chat to assist you if you have questions while using our site or regarding your order. When you sign up for our premium services we will share your name, billing address and credit card information as necessary for the third party to provide that service. These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for promotional purposes. 

Contributions to RatePoint. Content such as a Business or Product Review submitted by any User is considered public and non-confidential by RatePoint and shall not be treated as personal or proprietary information. Such Content may be aggregated by User and made available to all Users of RatePoint. RatePoint does not monitor, review or edit contributions to the Site and/or Services. Users should refrain from including any Personal Information or other private or confidential information in their Content. In no event will RatePoint be liable for disclosure of such Personal Information or other private or confidential information that is included in User Content. 

Other Disclosures. We may disclose your Personal Information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site, and when we believe release is appropriate to enforce or apply our Terms of Service and other agreements; in connection with an actual or proposed corporate transaction or insolvency proceeding involving all or part of the business or asset to which the information pertains; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of RatePoint, our Users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. In the event that we are legally compelled to disclose your Personal Information to a third party, we will notify you unless doing so would violate the law or a court order. 

### 3\. COMMUNICATIONS FROM RATEPOINT

Special Offers and Updates. As part of the service you will receive information on new RatePoint products and services, RatePoint, will occasionally send you e-mails with information on products, services, special promotions or newsletters or other information that we think may be of interest to you. If you decide you not wish to receive such communications, you may opt-out by changing your user preferences on the User Profile Page. 

Service-Related Announcements. We will send you service-related announcements when it is necessary to do so. For instance, to notify you of Site and/or Services maintenance and/or updates, we might send you an e-mail. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account. 

Customer Service. Based upon the information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming e-mail to verify your e-mail address, and, if you provided us with a mailing address or phone number, we may contact you via mail or telephone to verify your account information. We will communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. We may also use your e-mail address to respond to questions from you, provide information about the Site and/or Services, invite you to participate in new services and research programs, and/or inform you of significant changes to this Privacy Policy. If your contact information is outdated or inaccurate, we may not be able to send you e-mails or notify you about changes to this Privacy Policy. 

RatePoint User Profile. During the user rating process, you may create a User Member Profile. The non-Personal Information you provide such as your chosen display name, regional location, and review data in your user rating process will be viewable by any User, however, your e-mail address, password, and telephone number will not be visible to other Users. However, with your permission, this information may be shared with the RatePoint Business Member that you are rating. 

RatePoint Business Member Profile. During the registration process, you may create a Business Member Profile. The non-Personal Information you provide such as Business name, address, phone number and website in your Business Member profile will be viewable by any User, however, your name, e-mail address and password will not be visible to other Users. 

### 4\. ACCESS TO PERSONAL INFORMATION AND BUSINESS MEMBER PROFILE

You may view your Personal Information at any time by visiting your Profile Page. If your Personal Information and/or Business Member Profile changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update or delete inaccuracies within your Personal Information and/or Business Member Profile or deactivate your account by contact RatePoint at support@ratepoint.com

### 5\. SECURITY

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

If you have any questions about RatePoint security, you can e-mail us at security@ratepoint.com. 

### 6\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. 

### 7\. CONTACT US

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us at: privacy@ratepoint.com.
